Guide to the George Amberg and Robert Gessner Papers MC.199
New York University Archives
- Series V: Writings
  - Subseries B: Writings of Robert Gessner
    - Television Goes to College, 0 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Includes film programs 1957-1958
    - Treason, 0 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Two Sides to the Equator: an original screen treatment, 0 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      By Harold and Robert Gessner
    - Untitled Folder - "There is an African at the Gate", "Seven Faces of Time", "Teaching the Screenplay", 0 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Folder - "Youth at the Studio Gate", "In Search of the Third Eye", "The Power Behind Polish Films", 0 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "We've Eliminated Every Neurosis but Jealousy", 0 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Writings on Cinema, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Writings - Notebooks, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Writings - Notebook, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Writings - Poetry, Prose, Score, 1934-1935, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "The Year They Stopped the Commercials", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Films
  - About Town
    - No Slate Wanamaker's, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-1,2
    - Metro Museum, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-3,4,5
    - Metropolitan/Opera Ballet, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-6,7,8,9,10,11
    - U.N. Building, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-12,13,14
    - New U.N. Stuff, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-15,16,17,18,19,20
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-21,22,23,24,25,26
    - U.N. + Boids + Round or Square Shot, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-27,28,29,30,31
    - Untitled, from Around Town: UN, Metropolitan, Mod. Art, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-33,34,35
    - People to U.N., 1952; 1 film reels MC199-37,38,39,40,41,42,43,44
    - Bldgs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-46,47,48,49,50,51,52
    - Steuben Store, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-53,54,55,56,57
    - Out Pedestrians, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-59,69,61,62,63,64,65,66
    - Around Grand Central (turn into darkness), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-58
    - On 47[41?] Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-67,68,69,70,71,72,73,74,75,76,77,78,79
    - Day Store Window, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-80
    - Pedestrians, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-81,82,83,84,85,86,87,88,89,90
    - Untitled from Around Town: Polish+Sweep, Night Mat'l; subway, cars + cabs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-91,92,93,94,95,96
    - Subway Uptown, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-97,98
    - Untitled from Around Town: Polish+Sweep, Night Mat'l; subway, cars +cabs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-99,100,101,102,103,104,105
    - Subway, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-106,107,108,109,110,11
    - Polish + Sweep, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-112,113,114,115,116,117
    - Ferry Area People Pass 5+10, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-118,119,120
    - Lever House, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-121, 122,123
    - Lever Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-124,125,126
    - Lever House Interior, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-127,128,129,130
    - Untitled from Around Town: Lever House, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-131
    - Untitled from Around Town: Lever House 1, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-132
    - South Ferry Area - With Milling People, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-133,134,135,136,137
    - Ferry Area - Passing Pillared Bldgs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-138,139,140,141
    - Ferry - People at Bus Stop, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-142,143,144,145,146,147,148
    - Ferry High Angle People, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-149,150,151,152
    - Nite Store Windows, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-153,154,155,156,157,158,159,160,161,162,163,164
    - Night Manhattan Bldgs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-165,166,167
    - Out Dusk To Night Dissolve, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-168
    - Day To Night, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-169,170,171,172,173,174
    - Nite Bldgs, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-175
    - Window with Mirror Ball, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-176
    - Out Bldgs at Night, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-177
    - Night Pedestrians, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-178,179,180,181,182,183,184,185
    - Window-Panto Street (NSG), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-186
    - Winter Garden, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-187
    - Greek Theater, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-188,189,190
    - Tavern on the Green, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-191,192,193,194
    - Spaghetti Joint, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-195,196,197,198
    - People Theatre Marquees, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-199,200,201,202,203,204
    - Theater Audience, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-205,206,207,208,209,210
    - L.S. NY High Angle, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-218,219,220
    - Chinatown 1, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-221
    - Chinatown 2, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-222
    - Posters (Beethoven), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-223,224
    - LS Time Square Night, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-225
    - Untitled from Around Town: March of Time, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-226
    - Skyscrapers, wall st., 1952; 1 film reels MC199-227,228,229,230,231,232,233,234,235,236,237,238,239,240,241,242
    - Constuction, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-243,244,245,246,247,248,249,250,251
    - NY Parks (Out), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-252,253,254,255,256
    - E. River Drive, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-257,258,259,260
    - Uptown, Side Bridge, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-261
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-262
    - Skyscrapers, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-263,264,265
    - Smoky out stop motion manhattan, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-266
    - Cities + Bldgs Nig, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-267, 268
    - Grand Central Out, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-269
    - Treas. Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-270
    - Out Modern Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-271
    - Outtake Park Ave, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-272
    - Bob Walks to School, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-273,274,275,276,277,278,279,280,281,282,283
    - Opening Shop French Line, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-284,285,286,287
    - Gallery, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-288, 289,290,291,292
    - Empire Theater, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-293,294
    - Bank, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-294,295,296
    - Piano Store, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-297,298,299,300,301
    - Bali Theater, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-302,303,304
    - Fruit Market, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-305,306,307
    - Bob Walks to School Trims, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-308,309,310,311
    - Polishing sweeping fruit on stand (lift), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-312,313
    - Untitled from Around Town: Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-314
    - Door Lock, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-315,316,317
    - Untitled from Around Town 1: Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-315,316,317
    - Untitled from Around Town 2, Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-318,319,320
    - Untitled from Around Town 3, Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-321,322,323,324
    - Out-Park Ave, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-325
    - Stage, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-211,212,213,214
    - Central Pk Boats, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-215,216,217
- Series VII: Non-English Material
  - Box 14: Assorted Papers (film studio promotional material, film periodicals, typewritten memos, posters, art catalogs), 0 (Box 14)
    barcode#:31142042278039
  - Box 15: Subject Files (film index cards with attached newspaper clippings, 1930s-1960s) (Box 15)
    This box contains an alphabetically filed collection of index cards, on which are printed newspaper clippings about feature films. The clippings provide information about the film's premise, the actors, the director, and local showing times. The films included in the box range in date from the 1930s to the 1960s.
    barcode#:31142042278047
  - Box 16: Photographs (prints from UNESCO Archives, portraits of filmmakers and film subjects) (Box 16)
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks
  - Treason, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Robert Gessner, 1945-1972 (Box 18)
  - Scrapbook compiled by Gessner on instruction at NYU, 1936-1953 (Box 19)